Guide to the Edmund McAshan Dupree papers, 1916-1969 MS 448
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Edmund McAshan Dupree papers
1902-1969
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Dupree, Edmund McAshan
MS 448
1 Linear Feet (1 box and 1 map drawer)
This collection includes photographs, certificates, news clippings, typescripts, and awards dealing for the most part with Edmund McAshan Dupree's undergraduate career at Rice Institute and his class' 25th Anniversary Reunion in 1941.
Biographical / Historical
Edmund McAshan Dupree was the first student to register at Rice Institute and was the recipient of the first degree in 1916. After graduation with a degree in Electrical Engineering he joined General Electric Company in New York and in 1922 established his own firm, Star Electric and Engineering Company, on April 1, 1922 in Houston, Texas.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes photographs, certificates, news clippings, typescripts, and awards dealing for the most part with Edmund McAshan Dupree's undergraduate career at Rice Institute and his class' 25th Anniversary Reunion in 1941.
Access Restriction
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Edmund McAshan Dupree, August 1996.
Index Terms
Subjects
College students -- Texas; Universities and colleges
Document Types
photographs; letters (correspondence); clippings (information artifacts)
Subjects (Persons)
Dupree, Edmund McAshan
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University
- Series I: General files, 1922-1969; 42899
  - Diplomas, 1922-1948; 42908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memorial book, 1969; 42907 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1941-1969; 42906 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Rice Engineering Alumni, 1941-1942; 42905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Star Electric, 1921-1926; 42904 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Coat of arms, hand drawn (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: Photographs, 1902-1941; 42893
  - Photographs, 1902-1941; 42898 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Scope and Contents
    Contents include: Edmund Dupree ca. 10 years of age; Class of 1916 on Registration Day; E.M. Dupree, E.O. Lovett, et al., First commencement; E.M. Dupree as a young man; First Store of Star Electric and Engineering Co., Inc., owned by E.M. Dupree, 1921; E.M. Dupree and two unidentified men with airplane (framed June 26, 1928); E.M. Dupree and two unidentified men, sitting (framed June 26, 1928); Unidentified man with airplane (framed June 26, 1928); E.M. Dupree, E.O. Lovett, et al. at 25th anniversary of first commencemen,t 1941; E.O. Lovett Speaking at 25th Reunion, 1941; Members of First Graduating Class looking at Sallyport at 25th reunion, 1941; E.M. Dupree and other members of class at 25th reunion, 1941
- Series III: Oversize, 1928; 42879
  - Newspaper clipping U.S. Army Reserve Officers Association, 1928-07-22; 42880 (Drawer 35, Item 10)